Well,
Democratic socialist and front runner
in the New York City mayoral race,
Zoran Mamdani,
sat down with Martha McCallum for a rapid fire
interview ahead of tonight's mayoral debate.
Mamdani gave several elusive answers,
including this apology to the men and women of the NYPD
for calling them, among other things, racist.
Watch.
Do
we have that, Sat?
If not, we'll go on.
Mamdani says it's too early to award credit
for the ceasefire between Israel and Hamas.
Watch here.
And we're just going to keep rolling.
Police officers that I spoke to,
they don't want a behind closed doors apology.
They want
a broad public apology
for the things that you suggested about them.
Will you do that
right now?
Absolutely.
I'll apologize to police officers
right here,
because this is the apology that I've
been sharing with many rank and file
officers.
And I apologize because of the fact that
I'm looking to work with these officers.
And I know that these officers,
these men and women who serve in the NYPD,
they put
their lives on the line every single day.
Yeah, well, we already knew that.
Mamdani says it's too early,
however,
to award credit
for the ceasefire between Israel and Hamas.
Watch.
When it comes to the ceasefire, I am thankful
and I have hope that it will actually endure
and that it will be lasting.
And I continue to have concerns because I've seen reports still,
just this in the last few days,
that five Palestinians were killed by the Israeli military.
And that's what gives me pause about issuing any kind of praise
or celebration at a moment when it is still so in its infancy.
Would you give President Trump credit or not?
To any extent, credit or not?
I think it's too early to do so.
Too early to say.
But if it proves to be something that is lasting,
something that is durable,
then I think that that's where you give credit.
He also refused to answer whether he would call for Hamas to disarm.
Do you believe that Hamas should lay down
their weapons and leave the leadership in Gaza?
I believe that any future here in New York
City is one that we have to make sure that's
affordable for all and as it pertains to Israel and Palestine,
that we have to ensure that
there is peace.
And that is the future that we have to fight for.
But you won't say that Hamas should lay down
their arms and give up leadership in Gaza?
I don't really have opinions about the future
of Hamas and Israel beyond the question of
justice and safety and the fact that
anything has to abide by international law.
And that
applies to Hamas,
that applies to the Israeli military,
applies to anyone you could ask me
about.
And with just 19 days to go,
the Real Clear Politics average shows a large gap,
with Mamdani holding a 17 point lead
over former Governor Andrew Cuomo.
Republican Curtis
Lewa trails both with just under 13% support.
Kayleigh, I think frankly his answers were
not surprising,
but were alarming for many reasons.
And he continued to sort of hammer
this international court thing and the law and whatever,
but I just want to sort of hear
your takeaways on how you found him
during this interview and his answers.
I found him to be disqualifying.
And here's why.
You didn't have to listen to the whole
interview,
all you had to hear was this one line.
Mamdani said,
I don't have any opinions on the future
of Hamas after Martha pressed him twice about Hamas disarming.
That is a disqualifying statement.
I have said this many times on this show
and it is difficult to hear.
And I will say it again,
especially when a candidate
about to take over New York City is on the press piece
of winning, makes a statement like that.
There were babies put in ovens on October 7th.
And he doesn't know whether Hamas should disarm.
Well, let me share with you a few details.
Maybe you haven't been paying attention,
Mamdani.
These have come out just in the last few days.
Avinatan Or,
let's meet him,
let's pull up his picture.
He was put in a cage,
he just returned home,
five feet high,
kept in the cage the entire time,
oftentimes with five hostages.
So imagine two years in a cage, this man was in,
handcuffed to the cage for two years,
oftentimes with five other hostages.
Okay, well, let's meet
Ron Brozlovsky.
Ron Brozlovsky,
his mom said that he was kept by the bodies
of hostages in a room,
violently beaten,
tortured,
denied basic hygiene and then force fed
before he was left home.
And then of course,
we've brought up their picture
so many times,
Kefir Bebus, Ariel Bebus,
who were literally strangled by Hamas and killed.
And Zoran Mamdani cannot say whether terrorists
who killed those two little boys were disarmed.
You are disqualified from leading a grocery store.
You should be disqualified out of polite society.
Those two little boys should be here.
No terrorists should have arms.
And Tom,
I also wanted to play a little bit,
you know,
in keeping with his anti-Zionism, anti-Israel,
anti-Benjamin Netanyahu, anti-Semitism.
Here's his response when asked whether he would try to
arrest the Israeli prime minister
if he ever came to New York City.
Watch.
You have said that you would arrest Netanyahu
if he came to the United States.
I've said that this is a city that believes
international law and this is a city that wants to uplift
and uphold those beliefs.
The prime minister- The United States doesn't stand
by the International Criminal Court.
It hasn't signed the treaty for the
International Criminal Court.
The International Criminal Court, however,
has issued a warrant for the arrest of Benjamin Netanyahu.
As it has- What grounds in the United States
could you arrest him on?
As it has for Vladimir Putin.
I've said that I believe that we should uphold arrest warrants
by the International Criminal Court.
I found that telling,
Tom,
because he obviously doesn't know the law.
He doesn't understand the grounds.
And he's used to, I think, softball environments
where he can play on TikTok and he can create memes
and he can talk to impressionable 20-year-olds
down in the East Village.
But he has no idea when pressed with the facts,
the law,
or reality in any way what to do.
I saw him there as absolutely floundering at best.
He was floundering, but he sees the finish line.
And he's thinking, just stay on pace,
get across the finish line,
try not to answer the questions.
And the thing is, every answer he gave,
gave so much ammunition to Andrew Cuomo,
but I don't see Cuomo.
I don't see him anywhere.
And it's not entirely his fault.
I know he's talking.
I just don't see him.
I have not seen Andrew Cuomo since the primaries
because this guy sucks up all the air.
He's so outrageous.
Everything he says is a news headline.
And what is Cuomo gonna do?
That's unbelievable.
That's why we don't see Cuomo.
We don't see Cuomo because Cuomo doesn't wanna be
in front of the cameras.
Come on,
this was a man who's been governor of the state.
He's done so much.
Where is he?
He's crazy.
He's gotta get, I mean,
he needs to get out there.
I mean, seriously.
So that was part of it.
I apologize and I am willing to work with police officers
with his answer upon being pressed over and over
by Martha McCallum about keeping the city safe
with law enforcement.
Look,
he's willing to thwart our federal law as a country,
not signing on to the ICC and just do what he wants to do.
And now he'd love to sideline these officers.
He's willing to work.
These men and women already have jobs.
He's the one who wants the job to be able to lead the city.
He's not really interested in anybody
except for what he's going to do when he comes in.
And it is not going to be in the best interest
of keeping people safe
or holding our federal laws at hand.
So what, is he gonna personally sign on
to the international court?
I mean, is he going to sign on to the ICC?
The problem,
Ariel,
too,
that I see that's so frightening here
is that we see sort of this, to your point,
this groundswell of support in a lot of pop culture arenas.
So I've been noticing that there are pop-ups
in a lot of different apps,
including a lot of periodicals here in the city
like The Gothamist,
where there's ads for his coloring book
and his children's book about him walking through the boroughs.
There's t-shirts now with his circusy theme on it
that are sort of flooding everywhere.
So there's really a blanketing occurring,
frankly,
of venom,
because under which average New Yorkers,
I don't think understand the detriment
he would be to everyone's safety,
let alone the Jewish people here in this city
and the businesses and the like.
It is a very shiny veneer on a very terrifying monster.
I mean, listen,
should Hamas be disarmed?
Yes.
Should he have given President Trump credit
for his first phase of the Mideast peace deal?
Yes.
Simple answers.
Just answer it, yes or no.
Very simple.
Now, here's the thing.
He's trying to get this job to run this wonderful city.
It's the number one city in the market.
It's also an international city.
So people who are watching Martha's interview,
they want to know what's going to happen in the city,
not just because they those of us who live here,
but those who come to visit.
They so he did not answer.
What is his plan for New Yorkers?
How will he make the city affordable?
How does he plan to work with NYPD to make
the city safer like it was before COVID?
I felt very safe then.
How will he tackle the homeless issues?
These are things that whether you live
here or you visit this great city,
you need to know those answers.
Yeah,
he doesn't.
And the answers that he does provide are absolutely terrifying.